# Abdi Kadir Ismail

41 raglan road SE18 7JB Email: abdikadirismail100@gmail.com

https://www.linkedin.com/in/abdikadirismail/ Mobile number: 07391476589

Website: https://sites.google.com/my.westminster.ac.uk/abdikadirismail/

GitHub: https://github.com/AbdiKadirIsmail/

I am a full – time computer science student at the University of Westminster. I believe that being a hardworking, motivated and focused individual is crucial in the workplace. Also, having a range of useful skills developed over the years will help develop and diversify my individuality for any place. For example, teamwork skills, Dependability, adaptability, critical thinking, leadership skills and interpersonal skills. Moreover, I am a very punctual and organized individual willing to take responsibility for myself. As well as willing to look for any position to gain even more experience and gain and develop skills.

### **Technical skills**

Python -intermediate level C++ - intermediate level

Java – experienced level MySQL – intermediate level

JavaScript – beginner level Css – experienced level

Html5 – intermediate level Kali – beginner level

Unity – intermediate level Tensorflow – beginner level

## Education

## **BSc (Hons) Computer Science FT**

16/09/17 - 24/06/21

University of Westminster, Cavendish

#### Relevant modules:

- Enterprise Application Development,
- Security and Forensics,
- Advanced Interactive Media Development,
- Information Technology Security,
- Object Oriented Programming
- Database Systems.

For my final year project, I have implemented a python application incorporated with a **self-driving** and object detection in a simulation using a **Convolutional Neural Network** with **computer vision**.

Predicted grade: 2.1.

A-Levels August 2017

Harris Garrard Academy, Bexley

IT (Distinction), Sociology (E), Physics (U)

GCSEs June 2015

Harris Garrard Academy, Bexley

9 A-C including English and Maths

### **Work Experience**

Amazon logistics October 2018 – March 2020

Amazon Amazon UK Services Ltd.- Belvedere DBR1

Job role: Sortation Associate and operational Assistant

Responsibilities: I have carried out different duties such as Problem solving with drivers and missing/damaged parcels, sorting commercial deliveries for the next working day, loading and offloading from lorries, I have worked under the high-pressure workload and able to achieve my targets set out. I have gained valuable experience in which I have learnt communication and teamwork skills which played a vital role in these situations.

Transferrable skills: communicating, problem-solving, working under pressure and teamwork skills.

## **Work Experience**

#### **Wise Security**

April 2019 - September 2019

66 Stephen Rd, Bexleyheath DA7 6EE

Job role: Steward

Responsibilities: I worked at numerous large venues hosting large events such as The Royal Ascot, Copper Box Arena, Millwall FC and Tottenham FC. Such as manning gates, safety checks before each event through risk assessment. As well as, ingress and egress which is a part of the event management controlling the flow of people entering and exiting the venue.

Transferrable skills: crowd control, communication, teamwork, effectively spot potential trouble before it occurs, able to uses scanners, manning doors, and gates, directing and providing guidance to the public.

## **Work Experience**

## Showsec

September 2018 – October 2018

Regent House, 16 West Walk, Leicester, LE1 7NA

Job role: Steward

Responsibilities: I worked at numerous large events such as concerts e.g. Jays and Beyoncé's 'on the run tour' and Taylor swift - WNS at the London stadium to small events such as at the Hammersmith Apollo which hosts small bands. I have also worked at a handful of festivals such as Field Day and Junction 2. The roles which I take range from giving general guidance whilst manning doors to watching the exits/no go zones. I also am put in the PIT which is in between the stage and the audience to make sure the public are not jumping over and not get injured whilst on the other side of the barrier.

Transferrable skills: crowd control, communication, teamwork, effectively spot potential trouble before it occurs, able to uses scanners, manning doors, and gates, directing and providing guidance to the public.

#### Work Experience

RGIS

August 2018- September 2018

2000 E. Taylor Road, Auburn Hills, MI 48326

Job role: Inventory specialist

Responsibilities: RIGIS are an inventory specialists company hired by many stores to do stock counts in the stores range from high profile stores to smaller ones such as; M&S, Debenhams, Clinton cards, Sainsbury's, Home Base etc. The role I took whilst working for RIGS is to sort out the store's inventory management such as analysing data of the stock's stock to make sure there is enough inventory in the store. We do this by scanning items using a scanner either by a multi-scan or a single scan whilst meeting the store's requirements I.e. the accuracy of over 95% and done by a certain time like 4 hrs.

Transferrable skills: coordination, teamwork, communication, organization, time management, ability to work quickly under pressure, high level of attention to detail.

#### Languages

- English
- Somali

## Interests and other skills

First Aid/Basic life support on the 5th of July 2016.

Learning new programming languages: I enjoy learning new languages and how it compares to other languages.

Reading books: I enjoy reading a wide range of books from personal finance to fictional. I am also planning on reading autobiographies and other non-fictional books such as Death by Black Hole by Neil deGrasse Tyson.

Travel: I like to travel in my holidays, I have been to Sweden – Stockholm, France – Toulouse and Paris, Somalia – Mogadishu and Hargeisa, Ethiopia – Addis Ababa, Saudi Arabia - Jeddah, Medina and Mecca, Denmark – Copenhagen and Dubai and I'm planning to go to the USA sometime soon. I enjoy experiencing new cultures and learning new lifestyles/values people live in other places.

I also enjoy cooking – as it lets me experience different types of recipes for different types of food.

#### References

### **Noam Weingarten**

Senior Lecturer, Computer Science and Engineering

University of Westminster

115 New Cavendish Street

W1W 6UW

+44 20 7911 5000 ext 64578

#### N.Weingarten01@westminster.ac.uk

Noam Weingarten was my Personal tutor throughout my four years at the university as I completed my Bachelor of Science (BSc) Honours.

# Jeffrey Ferguson

Senior Lecturer, Computer Science and Engineering

University of Westminster

115 New Cavendish Street

W1W 6UW

44 20 7911 5000 ext 64740

## J.Ferguson@westminster.ac.uk

Jeffrey Ferguson was my lecturer for my Advanced Interactive Media Development module at the university.